GOUTHAM DEVA

godevawork@gmail.com | (603)-682-4516 gouthamdeva.com | linkedin.com/in/gouthamdeva | github.com/godeva

Career Summary

Senior Software Engineer with over five years of experience in full-stack development. Expert in **Python**, **Swift**, **Java**, **SQL**, **HTML/CSS/JS and Node JS** with a proven track record in building out front and back end mobile applications and full cycle internal products. Experienced in leading employees to produce B2C finance products.

Education

MBA, Quantic School of Business and Technology, Washington DC **BS, Computer Science**, Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

June 2022 - October 2023 August 2015 - June 2019

Work Experience

Fidelity Investments, Boston, MA

Senior Digital Assets Engineer, Fidelity Labs

Jan 2023 - Present

- Built a Swift-based digital asset aggregator app using SwiftUI, Async/Await, and MVVM architecture, preparing for an imminent App Store launch projected to serve over 100,000 users.
- Created multiple internal tools, including a dashboard actuator to democratize vendor outage alerts, boosting team awareness and improving project tracking efficiency by 80%.
- Developed an analytics dashboard using **Firebase** and **Pendo** to democratize digital asset usage insights across the firm, enabling data-driven decision-making and improving transparency.
- Designed and optimized RESTful API endpoints, improving response times by 15% through efficient coding practices and ensuring seamless app performance.
- Led multiple teams of engineers to develop a BTC IOS mobile social wallet using Agile methodology.

Blockchain Engineer, Fidelity Center for Applied Technology (FCAT)

June 2022 - Dec 2022

- Built and deployed Solidity smart contracts for a staking derivative prototype, configuring Ethereum Node hardware and software to test and gain insights into staking mechanics and operational requirements.
- Contributed to DeFi projects with Fidelity FCAT's Blockchain Incubator team, including writing scripts for DeFi
 arbitrage strategies and researching staking methodologies for future blockchain initiatives.

Software Engineer Fidelity Investments

June 2019 - June 2022

- Developed and optimized mutual fund RESTful APIs using Spring MVC, deploying to AWS EKS and reducing response times by 15%, while enhancing scalability and performance for internal and external clients.
- Designed and implemented the Periodic Investments API using OOAD, partnering with cross-functional teams to deliver tailored solutions for diverse consumer requirements.

NVIDIA, Santa Clara, CA

Software Engineering Intern

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

 Improved Tegra Boot and Power Management Processor (BPMP) codebase to achieve safety requirements under MISRA and ISO 26262 standards.

Projects

ContractAid: Automated Solidity Auditor

March 2024

 Developed a Solidity defect detection tool, winning top-three under the privacy award category at ETHDenver Hackathon 2024.

SolarChain November 2022

 Developed a DAO platform during the OpenAl Climate Change Hackathon using GPT-3 APIs and prompt engineering, enabling community voting on solar supply chain policies and delivering insights to support affordable solar energy initiatives.

WPI Capture The Flag (CTF) Cybersecurity Platform

April 2019

 Designed and managed the WPI CTF platform, engaging over 600 global participants and fostering a collaborative environment to enhance cybersecurity skills.